Cole, David L. Papers 5588
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  Reference documents relating to NCIP. "Collective Bargaining and Industrial Peace" by Cole; statement of D. L. Cole before U.S. Senate on Emergency Dispute Provisions of Labor Management Relations Act, (1972); memo from President, United Steelworkers of America (USA) to John T. Dunlop re experimental negotiating agreement; draft of Cole's thoughts (AAA Labor-Management Advisory Committee.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  Reference Documents relating to NCIP. "Avoiding Written Grievances: A Successful Program" by Robert McKersie and William Shropshire, Jr.; "Our Best Safeguard Against the Strike" by W. J. Usery of FMCS; memoranda concerning airline industry emergency labor disputes (1974) and Longshore strikes (1975).
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  National Commission for Industrial Peace, Report and Recommendations, May 1974.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  Material received from George Larney, Executive Director of NCIP. Includes correspondence; "The Quality of Work Program of the NCIP. A Statement of Intent".
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1974 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  Material received from George Larney, Executive Director of NCIP. Includes correspondence with Cole; "Significant Collective Bargaining Contract Expectations," January 1-January 31, 1974.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1974 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  Notes of Committee on Cement Industry. 1974.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  David L. Cole's statement before Senate Committee on Labor concerning National Emergency Disputes, 1971-72.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Applications for position of Executive Director, NCIP. Includes resumes, letters of recommendation, etc.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  Letters of congratulation to Cole for appointment as chairman of NCIP.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  Information on Stabilization Agreement Sheet Metal Industry.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 23, Folder 9)
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  Miscellaneous. Cole's notes; "Is the Strike Outmoded?"
- National Institute of Labor Education., 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  Cole was a member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Labor Education, 1957-58. Includes correspondence between George Meany and Ralph Campbell, President of the NILE and statement of purpose of the Institute.
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  Includes correspondence on the committee; executive committee minutes; Cole's letter of resignation from the Institute.
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  NILE's "Proposal to Promote Membership Participation in Labor Organizations."
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  Routine correspondence.
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 5)
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 6)
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  Financial statements of NILE.
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  Publications of NILE. "International Affairs"; "Pre-Retirement Education"; "Economic Education."
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  Publications of NILE. "Ethical and Moral Standards", "A Mental Health Program in Labor Organizations."
- National Institute of Labor Education. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  NILE activities report, press releases.
- National Mediation Board., 1954 (Box 24.1, Folder All)
  Arbitration board in the matter of a dispute between Hawaiian Airlines, Ltd. and certain of its Employees, represented by Air Line Pilots Association, International, Los Angeles, California, 8/12/54.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1943 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  Budget statements, 1943.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  Budget statements, 1945-46.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1944-1945 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  Includes routine correspondence 1944-45; agenda of meetings; etc.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1944-1945 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  Includes routine correspondence 1944-45; annual reports of the New Jersey State Board of Mediation.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  Includes routine correspondence; minutes of meetings.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  Includes routine correspondence; agenda for meetings.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  Includes routine correspondence; agenda for meetings; correspondence relating to the National War Labor Board.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  Includes routine correspondence; agenda for meetings; minutes; etc.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  Includes routine correspondence; agenda for meetings; minutes; information regarding disputes at Tidewater Associated Oil Co.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  Includes routine correspondence; first annual report of the Board; etc.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  Includes routine correspondence; minutes of meetings; agenda for meetings.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  Includes routine correspondence; information bulletins to Management and Labor regarding the War Labor Board,; establishment of the Office for Economic Stabilization, etc.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1942 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  Includes routine correspondence; report of the Camden County Mediation Panel, 1942.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  Includes routine correspondence; information on dispute between International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT) and Imperial Laundry.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  Includes routine correspondence.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  Includes routine correspondence; notes on dispute hearings.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  Includes newspaper clippings concerning the New Jersey State Mediation Board.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1943-1944 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  Includes Third Annual Report of Board to Governor Walter E. Edge, 1943-1944.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 27, Folder 1)
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 27, Folder 4)
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 27, Folder 5)
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1944 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  New Jersey State Mediation Board, cont. National War Labor Board's Steel Panel, Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation vs. USA, Report of the Panel, 1944.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board., 1965-1966 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  New York City's Bargaining Procedures (Tri-Partite Panel). Cole, member, Labor Management Institute Advisory Board. Includes correspondence with Robert Wagner and John Lindsay, mayors of New York City as well as a report of the panel to city officials. 1965-66.
- New Jersey State Mediation Board. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  New York City Employee Relations Program. Reports of the Task Force on City Personnel
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel., 1952 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  Includes information on workers' compensation cases for city employees; press releases concerning racial discrimination in Paterson; draft for improving sewage legislation; etc. 1952.
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  Correspondence concerning sewage improvement; zoning laws; assessments; etc.
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel. (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
  Information pertaining to the Board of Finance; correspondence; reports; and opinion on alleged irregularities.
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  Includes correspondence regarding Park Commissioners, Police Commissioners, etc.
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  Includes correspondence about Housing Commission.
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  Includes correspondence concerning Christopher Columbus Memorial Committee.
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  Estate of Josephine Bergen.
- Paterson, New Jersey, City Council. Cole, City Counsel. (Box 28, Folder 9-13)
  City Council cases, notes, etc.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy., 1961-1963 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  Includes memoranda from Edward Gudeman, Executive Director of the Committee; report of Committee on Fiscal and Monetary Policy for Economic Stabilization and Growth; article by Neil Chamberlain, "The Structure of Bargaining Units in U.S." 1961-1963.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  Includes papers on economic growth.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  Includes comments by Arthur Burns, George Meany and others on "The Problem of Economic Growth" and "The Problem of Full Recovery."
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy., 1961 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  Includes papers on the American Economy in 1961.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  Includes reports to the President on Automation.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 29, Folder 6-9)
  Includes papers on automation and technological change.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  Includes Committee statements on Corporate Pension Funds and unemployment.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy., 1946 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  Includes statement of Arthur Burns on the Employment Act of 1946 and papers on automation and technology.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 29, Folder 12-13)
  Includes correspondence and papers on automation and technology.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  Reports of Subcommittee 4 - Foreign Trade Committee.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  Includes minutes of meetings; statements on youth unemployment; taxes; and the peace corps.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  Includes reports on collective bargaining and industrial peace.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 30, Folder 7-10)
  Includes minutes of meetings, etc.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  Includes correspondence on collective bargaining.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  Reports on free and responsible collective bargaining and industrial peace.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  Includes general correspondence on committee work, correspondence from Walter Reuther, Willard Wirtz, Edward Gudeman.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  Committee reports on collective bargaining in the maritime industry.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  Includes correspondence and reports on collective bargaining.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 5-6)
  Includes papers and correspondence on committee's report on free and responsible collective bargaining.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  Includes papers and correspondence on committee's report on free and responsible collective bargaining; statements by David J. MacDonald, President, United Steelworkers of America and dissent of committee member Richard S. Reynolds, Jr. to the report.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  Includes papers and correspondence on committee's report on free and responsible collective bargaining; some of Cole's notes on the report.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  Includes drafts of statements on sound wage and price policies.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  Includes drafts of statements on sound wage and price policies; "A Description of Four Budget Concepts"; "Monetary Policy"; "Fiscal Policy".
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 31, Folder 11-12)
  Correspondence, papers, notes on pension plans.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  Correspondence concerning seminars conducted by the Committee on Private Adjustments to Automation and Technological Change.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  Includes correspondence; notes; reports on pension plans, manpower strategies, etc.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 3-4)
  Includes information on pension plans, automation, and technological change, manpower programs, etc.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  Report by Secretary of Labor on "Manpower Research and Training under the Manpower Development and Training Act."
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  Committee's reports and correspondence on sound wage and price policies.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  Includes related paper by John M. Clark on the wage-price problem.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  Statements, reports, correspondence on sound wage and price policies.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  Working paper on wage and price policy.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  Supplement to working paper on wage and price policy.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  Includes "Economic Guides for Responsible Collective Bargaining" by David J. MacDonald, President, United Steelworkers of America, "Employment, Growth, and Price Levels"; records of hearings before the Joint Economic Committee of the 86th U.S. Congress; memorandum from George Meany to members of the Committee
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  Includes memorandum to Committee members in benefits and problems incident to automation and other technological advance.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
  Includes papers presented at and correspondence related to the Conference on Fiscal and Monetary Policy sponsored by the President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  Includes papers presented at and correspondence related to the Conference on Fiscal and Monetary Policy sponsored by the President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy; Committee report on "Policies Designed to Ensure that American Products are Competitive in World Markets."
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  Includes papers prepared for the Committee: "Automation, Productivity, and Manpower Problems" by Derek Bok; "Technological Developments in Major American Industries" by U.S. Department of Labor.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  Includes papers prepared for the Committee: "Methods of Adjusting to Automation and Technological Change" by U.S. Department of Labor.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  "Public Policy and Private Pension Programs" by President's Committee on Corporate Pension Funds and Other Private Retirement and Welfare Programs.
- President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  Miscellaneous correspondence.
- President's Commission on National Goals., 1960 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  President's Commission on National Goals. Includes article on technological change and correspondence related to this article. 1960.
- Railroad Board., 1949 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  Includes Cole's own notes on the Board. 1949.
- Steel Panel., 1944 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  Includes Cole's notes on cases heard by the panel. 1944.
- Taft-Hartley Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare., 1954 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  President's recommendations for changes in the Labor Management Relations Act. Includes Cole's statement before the Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare for changes in the Labor Management Relations Act. 1954.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision., 1959 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  Includes Cole's recommendations for handling of major labor disputes, correspondence with John F. Kennedy and Archibald Cox. 1959.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  Includes directory of Panel members; correspondence with members, Archibald Cox, Arthur Goldberg, and Willard Wirtz.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  Includes paper on NLRB organization and procedure; drafts of proposed changes in the legislation.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  Includes alternative drafts for proposed changes in amendments concerning contract bar and other sections of the Act, also paper on NLRB organization and procedure.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  Includes "Amendments Relating to the Organization and Procedure of the National Labor Relations Board."
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  Includes report of the Panel to the Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare on the Organization and Procedure of the NLRB, also an act to amend the NLRA by revising the organization and procedure of the NLRB.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  Includes correspondence with Advisory Council members; travel vouchers for expenses incurred on Committee work.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  Includes visions of national emergency provisions.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  Includes revisions of national emergency provisions.
- Taft-Hartley Advisory Panel on Taft-Hartley Revision., 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  Androscoggin Mills, et al. Includes statements on behalf of the committee in the matter of the Textile Directive Steering Committee vs. the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA); other statements of facts of disputes as well as general facts and figures regarding rates of pay, job classifications, etc. 1945, 1946.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  Duplan Corporation. Includes rulings, correspondence, petitions for approval of wage rate structures for Office Employees and Foremen.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1945 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  Duplan Corporation. Includes rulings, correspondence, petitions for approval of wage rate structures for Office Employees and Foremen; analysis of proposed straight-time hourly increases Section (3) of Textile Directive Order of February 20, 1945.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  Includes comparisons of wage rate change plans, correspondence, agreement between Duplan and TWUA.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  Includes several petitions for approval of wage rate structures for Office Employees and Foremen, also includes correspondence regarding disputes in the Duplan corporation.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  Pepperell Manufacturing Co. and others. Includes agreements, correspondence, rulings, etc.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1944 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  Pepperell Manufacturing Co. and others. Includes wage scales, correspondence etc.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  Cole's notes. April 1943-February 1944.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1944 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  "Oral Argument on Behalf of the United Steel Workers of America in the matter of Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corp., et al., and United Steel Workers of America." September 27, 1944.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1944 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  "Oral Argument on Behalf of the Iron and Steel Producing Companies in the matter of Carnegie-Illinois Corp., et al., and United Steel Workers of America." September 1944.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1944-1945 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  Press releases, Second Regional Bd. decision. 1944-45
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  Second Regional Board decisions; Regional Wage Stabilization Manual; General Board orders.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  Instructional bulletin relating to wage and salary schedules; jurisdiction and procedure of Regional War Labor Boards; Executive Orders.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  Application of the "Little Steel" formula; "Wage Stabilization General Orders and Interpretations"; press releases; scales of approvable wage rates for white collar jobs.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  Press releases.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  Press releases, memoranda, and hearing notes.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  Includes memoranda, appeals procedures, press releases.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 37, Folder 4)
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  Includes correspondence; hearing notes; related article by Theodore Kheel; press releases; etc.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1945 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  Proceedings of the Commission meeting. July 31, 1945.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1945 (Box 37, Folder 7)
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1945 (Box 37, Folder 8)
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  Union Exhibits 1-4. Includes records of hearing between TWUA, CIO, vs. the Textile Directive Steering Committee.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  Union Exhibits 5-9. Includes records of hearings between TWUA and Textile Directive Steering Commission.
- National War Labor Board. Northern Textile Commission., 1943-1945 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  Union Exhibits 10-12. Includes records of hearings between TWUA, CIO, and Textile Directive Steering Commission.